Foster Gunnison, Jr. Papers
© 2006 University of Connecticut
Foster Gunnison, Jr. Papers.
undated, 1945-1994.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Gunnison, Foster, Jr.
55 linear feet.
From 1963 to 1975, Foster Gunnison, Jr. collected the records of the Eastern Conference of Homophile Organizations (ECHO), an early coalition of organizations seeking the creation of a national homophile organization, and the records of gay and lesbian organizations throughout the United States. He founded his own organization, the Institute for Social Ethics (ISE), "a libertarian-oriented research facility and think tank for controversial social issues", in the early 1960's. In 1967 Gunnison authored, and the ISE published, the pamphlet An Introduction to the Homophile Movement which outlined the history, aims and objectives of the movement and profiles of organizations active in the movement. The publication was subsequently presented to the Committee on Religion and Psychiatry of the American Psychiatric Association. The Foster Gunnison Papers are comprised of personal correspondence, organizational records, conference proceedings, student organization records, serial publications and periodicals, posters and fliers, buttons, newspaper clippings, and photographs.
MSS19960009
Biography
Foster Gunnison, Jr. was born in 1925 in Bronxville, New York. In 1944 he entered Haverford College and soon after transferred to Columbia University, graduating in 1949.
Gunnison moved to Hartford, Connecticut, in 1955 to pursue a Masters degree in psychology at Trinity College. After completing a second Masters degree at Trinity, in philosophy, he visited the New York City offices of the Mattachine Society. The year was 1964 and as Gunnison explained to receptionist Craig Rodwell, who would later emerge as a radical figure in the Society and an organizing force throughout the city, he had "known for some time that he was not developing into a heterosexual." Gunnison, who was in his early 40s, was looking for opportunities to volunteer.
Gunnison's decision to join the Mattachine Society, the nation's oldest homophile organization, established in San Francisco in the early 1950s, took place in the context of a growing public dialog about and resistance to the theories of Drs. Bieber and Socarides that characterized homosexuality as a pathological disorder. Within the rapidly growing and increasingly active homophile movement, organizations such as Mattachine, ONE and Daughters of Bilitis were joined by new groups such as the Society for Individual Rights and the Council on Religion and the Homosexual. Groups shifted attention from the dialog about the origins of homosexuality to efforts aimed at opposing discriminatory practices and promoting social reforms. In the late 1960s, few years before the Stonewall riots of 1969, student leaders and campus groups emerged as facilitating forces for change, bolstering the organizations' membership and in many cases their radicalism. Yet amid calls for centralization and unity within the movement, the new ranks challenged the "old guard" -- their leadership, agendas, and decisions on behalf of these organizations -- and facilitated the development of splinter groups and localized movements.
In the mid 1960s, Gunnison involved himself in the Eastern Conference of Homophile Organizations (ECHO), an early coalition of organizations seeking the creation of a national homophile organization, offering his services as secretary. In 1966, he was appointed Chair of the Credentials Committee for the North American Conference of Homophile Organizations. From 1965 to 1969, Gunnison collected the office and conference records of ECHO and NACHO, soon after expanding the scope of his collecting activities to include the records and periodicals of several gay, and some lesbian, organizations throughout the United States. During this period Gunnison founded his own organization, the Institute for Social Ethics (ISE), which he described as a "libertarian-oriented research facility and think tank for controversial social issues." Under the guise of ISE, Gunnison authored the pamphlet An Introduction to the Homophile Movement (1967).
In the early 1970s, Gunnison's interests and the direction of the ISE shifted. An avid cigar smoker, Gunnison turned his attention to smoker's rights and support for pro-smoking organizations. In 1984 he founded the American Puffer Alliance which he described as the first independent smokers liberation organization in the United States. The aim of the organization was to advocate for individual rights and the right of personal comfort. In 1985 APA began its annual Smoke-In Day, a counterdemonstration to the American Cancer Society's Smoke-Out Day. From 1992 to 1993, Gunnison authored a series of articles for American Smokers Journal entitled "A Smokers Manifesto."
Gunnison continued his association with the Society for the Preservation and Encouragement of Barber Shop Quartet Singing in America and smokers rights organizations through the 1970s and until his death in 1994.
Scope and Contents
The Foster Gunnison Papers are comprised of personal correspondence, organizational records, conference proceedings, student organization records, serial publications and periodicals, posters and fliers, buttons, newspaper clippings, and photographs. The homophile movement of the 1960s, gay and lesbian rights movements of the 1970s, smoker’s rights movement of the 1980s and 1990s, and several barbershop quartet organizations, as well as some of Gunnison's activities in relation to the movements and organizations, are represented in the collection. Bulk of the material dates from 1962 to 1993.
Arrangement
Materials related to the homophile movement can be found in Series I, Series II, Series III, Series IV, and Series V. Smoker’s rights materials are located in Series II, Subseries B. Materials pertaining to Barber Shop Quartet organizations are located in Series VI. Each series contains correspondence that relate to that specific movement or organization. The exception is correspondence to/from the Institute for Social Ethics in regards to gay, lesbian and transgendered organizations and acitvities. This correspondences can be found in Series I: Personal Correspondence. All photographs are located in Series VII.
Series I: Personal Correspondence ( 1965-1994 )
Series II: Institute for Social Ethics Archive ( undated, 1956-1999 )
Series III: North American Conference of Homophile Organizations (NACHO) ( 1966-1970 )
Series IV: Eastern Regional Conference of Homophile Organizations (ERCHO) and Eastern Conference of Homophile Organizations (ECHO) ( 1964-1973 )
Series V: Morris Kight Papers ( 1969-1973 )
Series VI: Society for the Preservation and Encouragement of Barber Shop Quartet Singing in America (SPEBSQSA) ( undated, 1945, 1956-1993 )
Series VII: Photographs ( undated, 1958-1993 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to alternative lifestyles, politics and publications. Periodicals from the collection document the activities of various gay and lesbian organizations in United States and Canada. The periodicals are cataloged and now searchable via the Library’s Catalog (HOMER). For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Gunnison, Foster.
Organizations:
Eastern Conference of Homophile Organizations (ECHO).; Institute for Social Ethics (ISE).
Subjects:
Gay liberation movement.; Homosexuality--United States.; Smoking--Law and legislation--United States.; Barbershop quartets.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Photographs.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.; Minutes.; Press releases.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Manuscripts.; Galley proofs.; Typescripts.; Photocopies.; Notes.; Interviews.; Speeches.; Newsletters.; Newspapers.; Broadsides.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated in.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Personal Correspondence, 1965-1994
  - Adkins, Warren to/from Gunnison, 1965 November - 1966 April (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Adkins, Warren to/from Gunnison, 1966 May - 1968 February (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Adkins, Warren to/from Gunnison, 1965 - 1994 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Alvarez, Walter C. to/from Gunnison, 1966 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Barker, Elver, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Benjamin, Harry, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Benson, Rod, 1966 February - April (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Benson, Rod, 1966 April (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Benson, Rod, 1966 May - June (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Benson, Rod, 1966 July - 1967 October (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Benson, Rod to/from Richard Inman, 1966 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - C, Select Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Del Boca, Bernardino, 1966 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - Duberman, Martin, Correspondence and Transcript, 1991 (Box 2:, Folder 14)
  - Duberman, Martin, Correspondence and Transcript, 1992 (Box 2:, Folder 15)
  - Duberman, Martin, Correspondence about Manuscript, 1992 (Box 2:, Folder 16)
  - Duberman, Martin, "Stonewall" manuscript, 1992 (Box 2:, Folder 17)
  - Francoise d'Eaubonne, 1971-1972 (Box 3:, Folder 18)
  - Hartford Advocate, 1988 (Box 58:, Folder 738)
  - Holm, Michael, 1970-1972 (Box 3:, Folder 19)
  - Inman, Richard, 1965 (Box 3:, Folder 20)
  - Inman, Richard, 1966 January - March (Box 3:, Folder 21)
  - Inman, Richard, 1966 April - June (Box 3:, Folder 22)
  - Inman, Richard, 1966 July - September (Box 3:, Folder 23)
  - Inman, Richard, 1966 October - December (Box 3:, Folder 24)
  - Inman, Richard, 1967 January - June (Box 4:, Folder 25)
  - Inman, Richard, 1967 July - December (Box 4:, Folder 26)
  - Inman, Richard, 1968 January - July (Box 4:, Folder 27)
  - Inman, Richard to/from Warren Adkins, 1965 January - July (Box 4:, Folder 28)
  - Inman, Richard to/from Warren Adkins, 1965 July (Box 4:, Folder 29)
  - Inman, Richard to/from Warren Adkins, 1965 August (Box 4:, Folder 30)
  - Inman, Richard to/from Warren Adkins, 1965 September (Box 5:, Folder 31)
  - Inman, Richard to/from Warren Adkins, 1965 October - 1966 April (Box 5:, Folder 32)
  - Inman, Richard to/from Other Correspondents, 1965 January - July (Box 5:, Folder 33)
  - Inman, Richard to/from Other Correspondents, 1965 July - August (Box 5:, Folder 34)
  - Inman, Richard to/from Other Correspondents, 1965 September - December (Box 5:, Folder 35)
  - Inman, Richard to/from Other Correspondents, 1966 January - March (Box 5:, Folder 36)
  - Inman, Richard to/from Other Correspondents, 1966 April - July (Box 5:, Folder 37)
  - Inman, Richard to/from Other Correspondents, 1966 July - November (Box 6:, Folder 38)
  - Inman, Richard to/from Other Correspondents, 1966 December - 1967 May (Box 6:, Folder 39)
  - Inman, Richard to/from Other Correspondents, 1967 May - 1968 April (Box 6:, Folder 40)
  - Kutz, Paul, 1968-1969 (Box 6:, Folder 41)
  - Legg, William "Dorr", 1989 (Box 58:, Folder 739)
  - Martin, Bob, 1966-1968 (Box 6:, Folder 42)
  - Martin, Bob, 1969-1971 (Box 6:, Folder 43)
  - Martin, Bob, 1972 (Box 6:, Folder 44)
  - Martin, Bob, 1973-1975 (Box 6:, Folder 45)
  - Martin, Bob, 1976-1978 (Box 6:, Folder 46)
  - Martin, Bob, 1979-1981 (Box 7:, Folder 47)
  - Martin, Bob, 1982-1985 (Box 7:, Folder 48)
  - Martin, Bob to/from Other Correspondents, 1967-1975 (Box 7:, Folder 49)
  - Morgan, W. L. D. (Reverend), 1966 January - April (Box 7:, Folder 50)
  - Morgan, W. L. D. (Reverend), 1966 April - October (Box 7:, Folder 51)
  - Morgan, W. L. D. (Reverend), 1966 January - June (Box 7:, Folder 52)
  - Perlstein, Sandra, 1966-1968 (Box 7:, Folder 53)
  - Ramp, Jim, 1966, 1968 (Box 7:, Folder 54)
  - Richards, Gerald, 1967 (Box 7:, Folder 55)
  - Skaggs, James, 1966-1968 (Box 7:, Folder 56)
  - Slater, Don, 1966 January - 1967 September (Box 7:, Folder 57)
  - Slater, Don, 1967 October - 1969 May (Box 7:, Folder 58)
  - Strait, Guy, 1966-1967 (Box 7:, Folder 59)
  - Warner, Arthur, 1968 (Box 8:, Folder 60)
  - Warner, Arthur, 1969 February - April (Box 8:, Folder 61)
  - Warner, Arthur, 1969 May - December (Box 8:, Folder 62)
  - Warner, Arthur, 1970 (Box 8:, Folder 63)
  - Warner, Arthur, to/from Other Correspondents, 1967-1969 (Box 8:, Folder 64)
  - Wiesbauer, Henry, 1966-1968 (Box 8:, Folder 65)
- Series II: Institute for Social Ethics Archive, undated, 1956-1999
  - Subseries A: Related to Homophile Movement, 1956-1999
    - Organizations
    - Advocate, 1967-1984 (Box 8:, Folder 66)
    - Albany Trust Correspondence, 1965-1972 (Box 8:, Folder 67)
    - Albany Trust, Supporting Material, 1966-1972 (Box 8:, Folder 68)
    - American Association of Religious Crusaders, 1968 (Box 8:, Folder 69)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1967 (Box 9:, Folder 70)
    - Association for Social Knowledge, 1966-1968 (Box 9:, Folder 71)
    - Atwater Steam Baths/Atwater Club, 1965-1967 (Box 9:, Folder 72)
    - The Body Politic, 1979 (Box 9:, Folder 73)
    - Calendars, 1988 (Box 9:, Folder 74)
    - California Association of Private Societies, 1967-1968 (Box 9:, Folder 75)
    - Campaign for Human Equality, 1970-1972 (Box 9:, Folder 76)
    - Center for Dialogue, 1966-1968 (Box 9:, Folder 77)
    - Center for Lesbian and Gay Studies, 1990-1992 (Box 58:, Folder 740)
    - Central Ohio Mattachine Society, 1968-1969 (Box 9:, Folder 78)
    - Chicago Gay Alliance, 1972 (Box 9:, Folder 79)
    - Christopher Street Liberation Day Committee, Accounts, 1970 (Box 9:, Folder 80)
    - Christopher Street Liberation Day Committee, Bulletins and Reports, 1970-1972 (Box 9:, Folder 81)
    - Christopher Street Liberation Day Committee, Fliers, 1970-1977 (Box 9:, Folder 82)
    - Christopher Street Liberation Day Committee, Office Files, 1969-1973 (Box 9:, Folder 83)
    - Christopher Street West, 1972 (Box 9:, Folder 84)
    - Cincinnati Homophile Organization, 1967 (Box 9:, Folder 85)
    - Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights, 1986-1992 (Box 10:, Folder 86)
    - Connecticut Gay Task Force, 1976-1977 (Box 10:, Folder 87)
    - Corduroy Club, 1966-1968 (Box 10:, Folder 88)
    - Council on Religion and the Homosexual, Correspondence, 1966 January - 1967 June (Box 10:, Folder 89)
    - Council on Religion and the Homosexual, Correspondence, 1967 July - 1968 July (Box 10:, Folder 90)
    - Council on Religion and the Homosexual (New England), 1971 (Box 10:, Folder 91)
    - Council on Religion and the Homosexual (New York), 1971 (Box 10:, Folder 92)
    - Council on Religion and the Homosexual (San Francisco), 1965-1973 (Box 10:, Folder 93)
    - Council on Religion and the Homosexual (San Francisco), 1966 (Box 10:, Folder 94)
    - Council on Religion and the Homosexual (Southern California), 1965-1972 (Box 10:, Folder 95)
    - Daughters of Bilitis, Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 10:, Folder 96)
    - Daughters of Bilitis, Correspondence, 1968-1976 (Box 10:, Folder 97)
    - Daughters of Bilitis, Conventions, 1962-1968 (Box 10:, Folder 98)
    - Daughters of Bilitis, Promotional Literature, 1967 (Box 10:, Folder 99)
    - Daughters of Bilitis (Los Angeles), 1967 (Box 10:, Folder 100)
    - Daughters of Bilitis (New York), 1967-1968 (Box 10:, Folder 101)
    - Daughters of Bilitis (Philadelphia), 1968 (Box 10:, Folder 102)
    - Dutch Society of Homosexuals, Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 11:, Folder 103)
    - Dutch Society of Homosexuals, Supporting Material, 1971-1972 (Box 11:, Folder 104)
    - Elysian Fields, 1975 (Box 11:, Folder 105)
    - Evangelicals Concerned, 1977-1978 (Box 11:, Folder 106)
    - Festival of Harmony, 1969 (Box 11:, Folder 107)
    - First Church of One Brotherhood, 1956-1957 (Box 11:, Folder 108)
    - The Fountain, 1973 (Box 11:, Folder 109)
    - FREE: Gay Liberation of Minnesota, 1968 (Box 11:, Folder 110)
    - GALA, 1982-1985 (Box 11:, Folder 111)
    - Gay Academic Union, 1970-1982 (Box 11:, Folder 112)
    - Gay Activists Alliance, Canadian Gay Activists Alliance, 1971-1972 (Box 11:, Folder 113)
    - Gay Activists Alliance, New Jersey, 1971-1972 (Box 11:, Folder 114)
    - Gay Activists Alliance, New York, Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 11:, Folder 115)
    - Gay Activists Alliance, New York, Fliers and Announcements, 1970 January - 1971 March (Box 11:, Folder 116)
    - Gay Activists Alliance, New York, Fliers and Announcements, 1971 April - 1977 June (Box 11:, Folder 117)
    - Gay Activists Alliance, New York, Promotional Literature, 1970-1971 (Box 11:, Folder 118)
    - Gay Activists Alliance, Philadelphia and Rhode Island, 1971, 1977 (Box 11:, Folder 119)
    - Gay Activists Alliance, Washington D.C., 1972 (Box 12:, Folder 120)
    - Gay Community Center, 1970-1971 (Box 12:, Folder 121)
    - Gay Community News, 1974-1982 (Box 12:, Folder 122)
    - Gay Community Services Center, 1972-1976 (Box 12:, Folder 123)
    - Gay League for Responsible Broadcasting, 1975 (Box 12:, Folder 124)
    - Gay-Lesbian Arts Alliance, 1982 (Box 12:, Folder 125)
    - Gay and Lesbian Advocates and Defenders, 1982-1985 (Box 12:, Folder 126)
    - Gay and Lesbian Advocates and Defenders, 1986-1988 (Box 12:, Folder 127)
    - Gay and Lesbian Alliance of Greater Danbury, 1984-1989 (Box 12:, Folder 128)
    - Gay Liberation Front, Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 12:, Folder 129)
    - Gay Liberation Front, New York, 1969-1971 (Box 12:, Folder 130)
    - Gay Liberation Front, Philadelphia and London, 1970-1971 (Box 12:, Folder 131)
    - Gay Liberation Front, Los Angeles, 1970 (Box 12:, Folder 132)
    - Gay Liberation Front, San Francisco, 1970 (Box 12:, Folder 133)
    - ay Liberation Front, University Chapters, 1970-1973 (Box 12:, Folder 134)
    - Gay Officers Action League, 1986 (Box 12:, Folder 135)
    - Gay People's Alliance, 1972-1974 (Box 12:, Folder 136)
    - Gay Religious Liberals Conference Committee, undated (Box 58:, Folder 742)
    - Gay Rights Advocates, 1978-1979 (Box 12:, Folder 137)
    - Gay Switchboard, 1972-1974 (Box 12:, Folder 138)
    - Gay Task Force, American Library Association, 1978-1988 (Box 12:, Folder 139)
    - Gay and Women's Alliance for Responsible Media, 1976 (Box 12:, Folder 140)
    - Gayellow Pages, Renaissance House, 1973-1975 (Box 12:, Folder 141)
    - Gayellow Pages, Renaissance House, 1976-1988 (Box 12:, Folder 142)
    - GEMS, 1992 (Box 58:, Folder 741)
    - George W. Henry Foundation, Correspondence with Alfred Gross, 1966-1967 (Box 12:, Folder 143)
    - George W. Henry Foundation, Correspondence with Alfred Gross, 1967-1968 (Box 12:, Folder 144)
    - George W. Henry Foundation, Correspondence, General, 1966-1968 (Box 12:, Folder 145)
    - George W. Henry Foundation, Literature and Office Material, 1966-1971 (Box 13:, Folder 146)
    - George W. Henry Foundation, Reports, 1963-1967 (Box 13:, Folder 147)
    - George W. Henry Foundation, Reports, 1968-1972 (Box 13:, Folder 148)
    - George W. Henry Foundation, Speeches by Alfred Gross, 1965 (Box 13:, Folder 149)
    - George W. Henry Foundation, Speeches by Alfred Gross, 1966 January (Box 13:, Folder 150)
    - George W. Henry Foundation, Speeches by Alfred Gross, 1966 January - August (Box 13:, Folder 151)
    - George W. Henry Foundation, Speeches by Alfred Gross, 1966 November - 1967 December (Box 13:, Folder 152)
    - George W. Henry Foundation, Speeches by Alfred Gross, 1968-1972 (Box 13:, Folder 153)
    - The Glide Foundation, 1968 (Box 14:, Folder 154)
    - Goliath Enterprises, 1973 (Box 14:, Folder 155)
    - Homophile Action League, 1970-1973 (Box 14:, Folder 156)
    - Homophile Community Health Service, 1971-1977 (Box 14:, Folder 157)
    - Homophile Effort for Legal Protection, 1972-1978 (Box 14:, Folder 158)
    - Homophile Union of Boston, 1970-1971 (Box 14:, Folder 159)
    - Homosexual Community Counseling Center, 1972-1977 (Box 14:, Folder 160)
    - Homosexual Information Center, 1971-1992 (Box 14:, Folder 161)
    - Homosexual Intransigent, 1969-1979 (Box 14:, Folder 162)
    - Homosexual League of New York, 1963 (Box 14:, Folder 163)
    - Homosexual Voters Advisory Council, 1966-1967 (Box 14:, Folder 164)
    - Human Enlightenment, 1971-1972 (Box 14:, Folder 165)
    - The Humanist, American Humanist Association, 1968-1969 (Box 14:, Folder 166)
    - Identity House, 1972 (Box 14:, Folder 167)
    - Institute of Living, 1969-1984 (Box 14:, Folder 168)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, Announcements, Bulletins and Fliers, 1967-1971 (Box 14:, Folder 169)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, Correspondence and Mailings, 1966-1968 (Box 14:, Folder 170)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, Correspondence and Mailings, 1969-1970 (Box 14:, Folder 171)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, Correspondence and Mailings, 1971 (Box 15:, Folder 172)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, Correspondence and Mailings, 1972 (Box 15:, Folder 173)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, Correspondence and Mailings, 1973-1974 (Box 15:, Folder 174)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, Correspondence and Mailings, 1975-1977 (Box 15:, Folder 175)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, Correspondence and Mailings, 1978-1979 (Box 15:, Folder 176)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, Correspondence and Mailings, 1981-1983 (Box 15:, Folder 177)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, Correspondence and Mailings, 1984-1985 (Box 15:, Folder 178)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, Correspondence and Mailings, 1986 (Box 15:, Folder 179)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, Correspondence and Mailings, 1987-1988 (Box 15:, Folder 180)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, Correspondence and Mailings, 1989-1993 (Box 16:, Folder 181)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide to Gay Pride,", 1971-1972 (Box 16:, Folder 182)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 100 New York, 1970-1971 (Box 16:, Folder 183)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 115-117 Long Island, 1970-1971 (Box 16:, Folder 184)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 122 Albany, NY, 1970-1971 (Box 16:, Folder 185)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 130-149 West NY, 1971 (Box 16:, Folder 186)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 146 GLF/Rochester, NY, 1971 (Box 16:, Folder 187)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 148 GLF/Cornell, 1970 (Box 16:, Folder 188)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 150-196 Pennsylvania, 1970-1971 (Box 16:, Folder 189)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 198 Human Enlightenment, 1970 (Box 16:, Folder 190)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 200 Washington D.C., 1970-1971 (Box 16:, Folder 191)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 210 Baltimore, 1970-1971 (Box 16:, Folder 192)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 240 Gay Alliance V.A., 1971 (Box 16:, Folder 193)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 378-379 Tennessee, 1970-1971 (Box 16:, Folder 194)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 402 GLF Louisville, 1970 (Box 16:, Folder 195)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 432-452 Ohio, 1970-1971 (Box 16:, Folder 196)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 481-482, Michigan, 1970-1971 (Box 16:, Folder 197)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 606 Chicago, 1970-1971 (Box 16:, Folder 198)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 631 St. Louis, 1971 (Box 16:, Folder 199)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 750-754 Texas Organizations, 1971 (Box 16:, Folder 200)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 802-803 Colorado, 1971 (Box 16:, Folder 201)
    - Institute of Social Ethics, "Gunnison's Guide," 895 The Ladder, 1970 (Box 16:, Folder 202)